JOHN MAZZUCCO

johnmazzucco.codes john.mazzucco@gmail.com Mississauga, ON

About Me

I attended Seneca College and graduated with a Computer Networking and Technical Support Diploma. Shortly after, I joined Stewart Title Guaranty Company as an IT Helpdesk Technician. I then made the decision to pursue a career in Web Development and transitioned to a Business and Quality Assurance Analyst role in the Product Development team. There, I worked alongside developers and gained valuable experience creating mockups and user stories, gathering business requirements, and testing. After 5 years with Stewart, I made the decision to focus on my education full-time and enrolled in Bitmaker Labs' Full Stack Web Development course. This was a challenging and intensive program where I learned key foundational skills and current trends in the Web Development space. I am currently seeking an exciting opportunity in the Toronto area as a Junior Web Developer while volunteering as a Web Developer for NeuroTechX, a non-profit organization.

Projects

AMAZON AFFILIATES

A Chrome extension that stores Amazon Affiliate IDs and automatically adds a selected ID to the URL when visiting amazon.com.

SEATYOURSELF

A clone of OpenTable, built with Ruby on Rails, that allows users to find nearby restaurants via Google Geolocation and book fictitious reservations.

CROWDREVIEW

A Ruby on Rails app that allows users to search for scientific journal articles using the Public Library of Science API. To improve the performance of the search function, articles are stored in a local database once they are retrieved from the API. Each article has a comments section and can be added to a "favourites" list by a User.

Experience

WEB DEVELOPER, NEUROTECHX; REMOTE - 2016-PRESENT

Volunteering on a small team of neurotechnology enthusiasts to create a new website for the NeuroTechX non-profit organization. During this opportunity, I gained experience using the Facebook, Twitter, Meetup and Slack APIs, furthered my understanding of AJAX requests, and learned to code in PHP.

JR BUSINESS AND QUALITY ASSURANCE ANALYST, STEWART TITLE; TORONTO, ON - 2014-2015

A part of a team of 15 analysts and developers that deployed and maintained a web application that was the company's primary channel of sales. Agile principles were used during each phase of the development life cycle. Responsibilities included gathering business requirements, creating user stories, mockups, and thoroughly testing the application with verification and regression testing methods.

IT HELP DESK TECHNICIAN, STEWART TITLE; TORONTO, ON - 2010-2014

Provided technical support for over 200 local and 50 international employees, along with 3 team members. Responded to user requests and issues regarding computer hardware, software, accounts, permissions, printers, VoIP phones, and smartphones. Some key projects were upgrading a Nortel phone system to VoIP and rolling out virtual machines to all users.

Education

Bitmaker Labs, Toronto, ON – Immersive Full Stack Web Development Course, 2015 Seneca College, North York, ON – Computer Networking and Technical Support Diploma, 2009

Proficiencies